Welcome to our training on resolving product matching errors.
At Amazon we use product matching to simplify the listing process.
Instead of putting every seller's offer on a separate product detail page, we match new offers to
existing pages when products are already sold in the Amazon store.
That keeps sellers from having to recreate pages.
It also makes it easier for customers to find, compare, and purchase products.
At times you may encounter matching errors while listing a product because we think you're trying
to create a new detail page for a product that's already been listed.
In general, these errors occur for three reasons.
1.
The product ID you entered is associated with a different product in the Amazon store.
For example, you entered the product ID 12345 for a perfume, but that product ID is associated with
a room freshener.
2.
The product ID you entered is correct and is assigned to the same product in the Amazon store, but
one or more of the other product attributes you entered conflicts with the attribute information
of the existing product.
For example, you entered a brand name for a perfume that doesn't match the brand name of the existing
product.
3.
The seller SKU you entered is already assigned to a different product, either in your inventory
or the greater Amazon store.
Let's review how to resolve each of these listing errors.
If you receive a matching error for the product ID while listing, start by confirming that the product
ID you entered is correct.
Make sure it's the exact same product ID that appears on the product's barcode.
And make sure that the product ID you're using is part of the GTIN or Global Trade Item Number System.
The most common product ID or GTIN used by Amazon sellers is a UPC, but you might use an EAN, JAN
or ISBN too.
All GTINs are obtained from an organization called Global Standards 1 or GS1 for short.
After you've confirmed the product ID, review the error message you received.
It will include the product ID you entered as well as the ASIN or Amazon standard identification
number of the product we think your listing matches.
Use the ASIN we've provided to search the Amazon store and review the product we've suggested is
a match.
If the product we've suggested is the same one you're trying to list, enter the ASIN we've provided
in the product ID field to resolve the error.
Or if the product you're trying to list is different from the one we've suggested, reach out to
seller support and provide the full product information and the error message you received,
along with proof of ownership, like a GS1 certificate or images of the ID on the product.
If you receive a matching error for a product attribute while listing, you can follow a similar
process to resolve it.
Use the ASIN we've provided in the error message to search the Amazon store and review the product
we've suggested as a match.
If the product we've suggested is the same one you're trying to list, update the attribute value
you received an error for.
Be sure to match it with the attribute information of the existing product.
This will resolve the error.
Or if the product you're trying to list is different from the one we've suggested, you can update
the product ID or other identifying information to create a new product detail page.
You can also use the Fix Your Products tool in Seller Central to resolve product attribute errors.
To do so, open the main menu, hover over Inventory and click Manage All Inventory.
Then, on the Manage Inventory page, click Search Suppressed and Inactive Listings.
On the Fix Your Products page, select Incomplete Listings, then click Matching Conflicts.
Find the product you've received an error for.
Then click the Accept Amazon's Value button to update your attribute information with the value
we provide.
Or enter your own value and click the Save button.
The last kind of error you might receive while listing is for your Seller SKU or Stock Keeping unit.
SKUs are Seller Specific and every product you list needs to be associated with a unique SKU.
If you've entered a SKU that's already associated with a different product, either in your inventory
or the greater Amazon store, you'll need to delete your listing.
Then, recreate it using a unique SKU.
This concludes our training on resolving product matching errors.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!